This is a 1976 Ford Country Squire.
I don't like this car.
It's big. It's wasteful.
It's got stupid, fake wood
paneling on the side.
It's an L-T-D. L-T-D stands for "Limited."
You know what it's limited to?
How many of these damn things we can sell,
that's what it's limited to.
I'm hating every second of this,
but I'm doing it.
Because this car belongs
to a very special friend of mine.
And that's the only reason
it's on the show.
And she just bought this.
I don't even know why.
But I'm gonna find out today.
On a brand-new episode
of Comedians in Cars...
Getting aggravated.
You called for a comedian coffee service?
Constantly! They finally picked up.
[Sarah] I can't get over
how gorgeous this is.
[Jerry] Why is it gorgeous?
There's just a huge amount of glass.
You know, I grew up in a car like this.
I spent so much time
in the back of that car.
-God, smell it. A little bit of gas.
-[Jerry laughs]
Do you know when you smell in these
big old American cars?
-Yeah.
-A teeny bit of gas... which I love.
There's just so much space.
My kids are gonna freak out.
Well, of course there's
a lot of room. It's huge.
And there's still some storage space.
Yeah, so the packages can hit you
-as the car takes off.
-Exactly.
-Well, you probably deserve it.
-Yeah.
[both laugh]
That's a nice seat. Come on!
Did you feel it?
I honestly cannot believe
we are in this car and that it's mine.
Hey, what's up?
What do you think of this car?
[Jerry singing]
♪ I think it's time for that silly show ♪
♪ Where comedians in their cars go ♪
♪ They talk and laugh with coffee beans ♪
♪ And drink and stir
And wear blue jeans ♪
♪ So I'll get in that car ♪
♪ No need to go far ♪
♪ Sometimes on stage I won't come offie ♪
♪ Unless I get in a car for coffee ♪
Turn the... Yeah, I wanna hear it.
[turn signal sound]
When I was little,
that sound was like the score of my life.
You know, it was so loud.
Do you remember how loud turn signals...
They don't even make noise now.
Any car insanity, I love.
[Sarah] I have a lot of good memories
in a car like this.
And I have sentimental memories.
I'm wistful about some of it.
Some really great times
in my formative years.
[Jerry] I have to say,
I kind of like driving this thing.
Did you feel how it went
over the bumps? How nice it was?
Of course. I feel everything,
see everything, know everything.
I know.
[Jerry] You and I are very funny together.
We're both a little hyper-aware.
-Of little things.
-Of little things and...
-Bless you. Uh-oh.
-Excuse me.
You know, in the old days,
they'd have a box of Kleenex.
Or your mom would pull one out
or something.
[Jerry] Don't you love New York
going to work in the morning?
[Sarah] Love it.
Look at her.
Look at the lady. Looking good.
[Jerry]
How you enjoying the ride so far?
[Sarah] I love it.
I got so much glass. I can see.
There's almost no obstruction...
with all of 14th Street.
-Was your thought...
-Top.
Family vacation.
-All the luggage is up there.
-Right.
Kids on an Etch A Sketch in the back.
Mad Libs.
Water colors, and you don't have it.
You just wet the brush yourself.
-[Sarah] We going to the tunnel?
-[Jerry] Yeah.
What I would have done,
I would have made a left on Bleecker,
left on 10th,
and I would have taken 10th Street
straight over till 3rd,
and then come around
to the Midtown Tunnel that way.
-That's what we're doing.
-Okay.
-So next time we do this...
-Yeah.
...in this car, in that outfit,
we'll do it my way.
I'm kidding.
-[Jerry] I'm so hungry.
-[Sarah] I'm so sorry.
-I really just want a coffee.
-Well, do you want me to get...
I'm happy to run and get...
There's coffee right there.
[Jerry] Look at this lady. Hello.
How big an object does it take?
[Sarah] Gotta talk about that.
How do you like your coffee?
-Let me go with you.
-No, stay. You gotta watch this car.
If something happens to this car,
I will never forgive you.
-[Jerry] What do you think?
-[man] Grocery-getter. I like it.
[Jerry]
You can get a grocery with anything.
Who's with the car?
-Hi.
Could we get a small coffee
for this gentleman?
[Sarah] Hard to not stare
at that car, right?
[man] My father used to have
a whole bunch of these.
-They're worth something now.
-They are.
-[Sarah] Want me to hold that for you?
-Sure, thanks.
-The old-school cup holder, people.
-Yeah.
[Jerry] I feel the cup holder defines
our culture.
I'm not gripping anything.
People get in, "Where is the cup holder
in this car? This is insane."
And I first discovered it with Amazon.com.
They have the one-click ordering.
-Yeah.
-One click, that's it.
Need me to click twice?
I don't even want it anymore.
You think I got nothing to do but click?
You make it one click or I'm out of here!
[Sarah] So interesting,
because I think about the television set.
There was a period of time
in which we had to stand up
and go switch it, then sit down.
See what your experience was like,
sitting down, watching that show.
-Well, let's see how this is.
-Yeah.
[Sarah] But there are things that
I am sorry don't exist for my kids now.
The way we kind of communicated
with each other.
Or a busy signal.
The anticipation that a busy signal
can build up and up.
Yeah, yeah.
Someone coming to our house
because the phone was busy for so long.
She was in a rage,
one of my mother's friends.
Like, "Is Barbara there?"
"Well, she's on..."
"I know she's on the phone.
I've been calling for 45 minutes."
[Sarah] There are certain things
about that that I do miss.
[Jerry] I miss every second of it.
But I can't escape what, I feel,
must be some narcissism.
I grew up in the suburbs. Didn't like it.
-Always wanted to live in the city.
-Yeah.
Now I wanna live in the suburbs.
You want your kids to want out
the way you wanted out.
No, I just want them to live my life over.
-Yeah.
-That's narcissism.
[Jerry] Matthew has this great line
about when you get your kid a spoon,
you think, "What a great dad I am.
Look at me getting my kid a spoon."
-That is what we think.
-Yeah.
Why are we such horrible parents?
-Oh, my God. Are we horrible parents?
-I think so.
See, look at that.
Why are you so upset about it?
You've already run rings around
what your mother has done.
And that's not good enough for your kid.
[Jerry] This is probably
a longer conversation
about parenting that we've just had
than your mother had all told her life.
Because she never had time.
-And who cared?
-Plus, she was always in a rage.
Legitimately.
"I'm gonna slam you!"
I remember my mother saying,
"I'll turn around and slam you."
That's what she used to say.
My friend, Mark Schiff, says,
"Mothers don't have headaches,
they always have splitting headaches."
You don't think it could be
from screaming nine hours a day, do you?
[Sarah] Did you ever care
about a motorcycle?
[Jerry] I had many motorcycles.
And I obsessed in my young life,
"I'm either gonna be a motorcycle guy
or I'm gonna be a sports car guy.
I gotta decide who I am and what I am.
And that will be determined
by how I get around."
And there was a guy who worked
in my dad's shop. He was a motorcycle guy.
And he came in one day,
and it was pouring rain,
and he was soaking wet.
And I looked at him.
Here, I'm like 17 years old and I go,
"So, today, don't you wish you had a car?"
And he says,
"Nope. Just wish it wasn't raining."
-Wow.
-[jazz music playing]
[Jerry] Do you remember
Then Came Bronson with Michael Parks?
It was a great antihero
TV show of the '70s.
I'm gonna do the opening,
word for word.
Yeah, okay.
[Jerry] Michael Parks
was like TV Steve McQueen.
He pulls up to a light.
This is the opening of the show.
A guy in this car pulls up next to him.
He's got the Don Draper little hat on.
He's got the suit, he's got a
wife and kids and a job, and he's trapped.
He says, "Where you going?"
-Where to?
-Says, "Oh, I don't know.
Wherever I end up, I guess."
I don't know. Wherever I end up, I guess.
Wow.
Husband guy says, "Sure wish I was you."
Well, I wish I was you.
And Michael Parks goes,
"Yeah, well, hang in there."
Well, hang in there.
And he roars off.
Coolest thing I ever saw in my life.
[Sarah] You know, there used
to be a sign on buildings in New York
that basically said,
"No Irish, no show people..."
-What?
-"No..." Yeah.
-A "no Irish" sign?
-Not...
I might be embroidering
the story a little bit.
But basically, it was like,
"Show folks need not apply."
-Show folks?
-Right.
Irish. And show folks.
Well, I think there was
a certain sort of class of people
-that was thought of as beneath...
-Irish show folks.
-And God forbid you were Irish.
-The lowest.
Show folk.
We can't do that anymore.
That's not politic.
I believe Irish show folk
are allowed everywhere now.
[Sarah] So, here's what I was thinking of.
I might do a patty melt on rye bread.
I've never heard someone accent
the "bread" in "rye bread."
-I didn't mean to. Rye bread.
-Rye bread.
[Jerry] "I'll have some rye bread,"
I've heard that.
-"I'll have some rye bread."
-Rye bread.
[Jerry] I have not.
[Sarah] How did he get
the word out? How did he...
[Jerry] Good question.
Here's how he did it.
[ice cream truck music]
That's the ice cream man. I'm not kidding.
-Do you hear it? There he is.
-Yes.
[Sarah] Ah, that's a sound
that coincides with this car.
But here's the difference.
Just the other neighborhood kids had it,
not us. Not the Parker kids.
-[Jerry] No ice cream?
-[Sarah] A half-gallon of Breyers...
maybe once every two to three months.
And it was gone in about 24 hours.
And my mom was like,
"Who ate all the ice cream?"
[Jerry] Can't tell you
how happy it makes me
just driving on these streets
where I grew up.
So, imagine what a car or a bike meant
when you lived in a place like this.
It's like angel wings.
What role did your mother play
in your life?
Was there an exchange of,
"How was your day?"
-No.
-Was there music on?
-[Jerry] Cha-cha.
-[Sarah] And what about the day?
How would she keep
her mind occupied? No TV?
-No.
-No radio?
-Wow.
[Sarah] Can you imagine sitting
in a quiet house?
-But did they hug you? Hold you?
-No.
-Kiss you a lot?
Did you see a smile on her face?
No one in my life has ever asked me
any of these questions.
Well, I'm really curious.
And look how interesting...
That house looks actually old.
[no audible dialogue]
Oh, classic chicken salad, Caesar.
-Do you have a preference?
-L'Oréal.
[laughs]
Hi, how are you guys?
-How are you?
-Good. How you doing?
[waitress] Something to drink?
-Chocolate egg cream.
-And a cup of coffee, please.
-And you can drink coffee all day?
-All day.
-It would give me horrible anxiety.
-I like the anxiety.
So, I'll have the patty melt on rye bread.
-Do you have rye bread?
-[indistinct]
Rye bread.
[Jerry] I do this bit with the kids.
It's called
"the guy who doesn't know where to look."
What's that?
Know when people tell a story
that goes, "So I get on the train."
Yeah.
And the guy,
"No, it's not actually there."
"So I'm walking down the street..."
[laughs]
And you look where the guy...
-That's so funny.
-You can have it.
You can do it in your family.
-Can't do it.
-Why?
Some things might be wasted
on four-and-a-half-year-olds.
Nothing is wasted.
-Holy cow!
-Yeah.
I've never seen it like that. Open-faced.
[waitress] Do you want Parmesan cheese?
[Jerry] It could use some cheese.
What do you think people think we're doing
that are watching us right now?
A new TV show, I guarantee you.
I know, but this doesn't look like a show.
Why would reason have anything
to do with what people think?
That's your best line of the day so far.
[Sarah] And I was thinking...
So, all these people are gonna go home
and they're gonna go to sleep
in their apartments.
Like, everybody sleeps.
Everybody's gonna lie down.
Think about it. All over the city,
there's just people sleeping.
It's so weird.
-You sound like you're high.
-And I'm not though, I know.
You really remind me of me.
-Really?
-I see why I exhaust people.
[laughs]
That's horrible.
Okay. Now, you told us
the perfect morning with an espresso.
First of all, to wake and be rested.
Number one, let's just start with that.
Take the kids to school,
which I genuinely enjoy.
It's Fall or Spring.
The kids are much easier
to get out the door.
They're much nicer about it.
You're not in as many battles about layers
and the government,
which I always bring
into the conversation.
-Why?
-Like, "The government says
you have to wear socks."
"Don't make me call the government."
That's a great parenting tip.
Yeah, the government.
Can I get you anything else?
-No. I couldn't imagine...
-No coffee?
-Wowza.
-Yes.
Here's a check take me and Larry Miller
used to do all the time.
"So, I thought maybe later
we could grab..."
You just keep talking,
-but your eyes can't help but react.
-Yeah.
So, I thought maybe
if you drove the car back that we could...
Are you waiting for me
to offer up some cash?
Should I feign...
How many more times
are you gonna laugh at that?
I don't know.
Okay, the check is $37.
-How much tip would you leave?
-Ten.
[sputters]
-You go to hell.
-That's not enough?
-No.
-Wait. You move the decimals.
It was a $40 check.
You would leave $8, would be 20%.
No. Am I... Somebody help me.
I'll help you.
Because everyone's gonna ask her.
"Oh, my God, you waited on Jerry Seinfeld
and Sarah Jessica Parker.
-How much did they tip you?"
-How much did...
What do you want her to say?
-Twenty bucks.
-Yeah. Is that what you want?
-Ten. You just move the decimal point.
-Okay, wait.
You're going to leave...
Wow. Big shot. Unbelievable.
-Gross?
-Disgusting.
-Garish?
-Vulgar.
No, it's lovely. I'm a total... [bleep]
-But for real, like, all joking aside...
-What is real?
You tell me what real is, and we'll
have gotten something outta this.
I'm really glad we are not married.
[laughs]
-[Jerry] Sarah, you drive.
-[Sarah] You serious?
-Don't you want to?
-Yes, of course I do.
[Sarah] But the seat's too far back.
Can we move the seat?
-Sure, there's a little...
-I remember my mom in the old days...
Yeah, the whole thing, you have to...
The entire family has to get
behind the moving of the seat.
On three.
[laughs]
-Oh, yeah.
-Look at you.
Look at the confidence. I love it.
You are really a mom now.
I feel like I'm a kid getting dropped off
to go bowling or a movie.
[laughs]
-Going north?
-Yeah, the black SUV with the...
-With the camera sticking out of it?
-Yes.
One of my other favorite takes.
This is similar
to the check take, the eye roll.
You go, "The one with the camera?"
And I go, "Yes."
-Oh, dear.
-Oh, dearie.
Merge, merging. Oh, dear.
[Jerry] That way, that way, that way.
-[Sarah] Can I do it?
-Yeah.
-[horn honking]
[Sarah] Hey, come on, what's up?
It's 1976. Get over it.
[Jerry] Oh, this seat belt is so brutal!
God, it just clicks and clicks.
-[horn honking]
-[Sarah shrieks]
Sorry. You're not gonna trust me,
I'm actually a really good driver.
-How's that seat belt?
-It's horrible.
I gotta hold it so it's not like
getting lap-band surgery.
I hope that... Sorry.
[laughs]
Oh, my God.
Why do they always have this on radios?
-The five and the four.
-I don't know.
-They've always had that on AM.
-You're right.
-Why the four?
-What is that?
-What is the four?
-I don't know.
Oh, my God. That's a great observation.
[Sarah] If this were my mom,
she would have had
Carole King Tapestry
playing on the 8-track.
The song about, "Hey, Dad,
can I borrow your car keys?" Harry Chapin.
That song, "Cat's Cradle,"
messed up a lot of dads.
And Harry Chapin died on this highway.
He had a massive coronary while driving
a VW Beetle on the Long Island Expressway.
And I recorded a song with him
right before he died.
-Get out of here.
-Yeah.
-You recorded with Harry Chapin?
-Me and my brothers and sisters.
♪ There are so many colors
In the rainbow ♪
♪ So many colors in the morning sun ♪
♪ So many colors in a flower
And I see every one ♪
♪ There are so many colors
In the rainbow ♪
♪ So many colors in the morning sun ♪
♪ So many colors in a flower
And I see every one ♪
♪ So many colors in a flower ♪
♪ And I see every one ♪
[Sarah] I hear James Wilkie talk
about his future,
and it just makes me wonder
what you thought about yours.
What you wanted to do,
what you loved to do.
Okay, here's what I thought
when I was his age.
"The world is great
because it has bicycles.
It has toys.
And it has cute girls."
And then I saw
my first Tampax commercial...
And I thought,
"There may be more to that thing..."
[laughs]
"...than meets the eye."
I knew the first two are solid.
-Toys, bicycles.
-Bicycles, right.
You didn't see
any weird bicycle commercials.
No. These are the things
that made the world great for me.
Yeah, yeah.
The world's gonna be great.
I'm gonna love this place.
I'm gonna love being a human.
Toys, bikes, cute girls.
There might be more to this one. Yeah.